

PERSONAL INFORMATION

NAME

Katherine Libbos

YEAR OF BIRTH

1980

Primary Email

KatieLibbos@hotmail.com

Cell Phone

587-894-4996

Location

Ottawa, ON

Katherine Libbos

ABOUT

Over the course of Katherine's career, she has worked in such capacities as a Business Operations and Financial Analyst, Inventory and Sales Analyst, Marketing Coordinator, Team Support and Administrator, Key Account Manager and Co-Owner & Operator of a Second Cup Franchise.

Katherine is known as an expert in analysis, data mining, forecasting, marketing, reporting, presenting, inventory management and process improvement, all with the intent to streamline business processes, increase revenue streams, maintain business relationships and monitor warehouse product levels.

With almost 20 years of experience in the areas above, Katherine is an excellent candidate to continue her career in the analysis, business operations and relationship management field, focusing on improvements for people and processes.

KNOWLEDGE AREAS

Systems

- SAP / BW BEx Analyzer
- Momentis
- Cognos
- Encompass
- AX
- FD
- Introduction to Python (11-week online course Stanford University)
- Self-training In HTML and CSS through Codecademy

Skills

- English (maternal), French (advanced), Swedish (beginner)
- Microsoft Excel, Powerpoint, Power BI
- Relationship Management
- Business Case Development
- Ability to work proficiently with all vendor and customer online reporting, data, inventory portals (1Screen, Retail Link, Capris, Aztec/IRI, InfoManager, Ad Dynamics, SharePoint, Commerce Hub, Supplier Hub, IDM, QuoteCenter)
- Reporting/Identifying trends
- Forecasting (monthly, quarterly, yearly) processes
- Data Entry/Typing 60 WPM

Industry Knowledge

- Retail
- Production
- Finance
- Consumer Packaged Goods
- Logistics

Methods

- Agile
- Six Sigma Process Improvement

Education

Glengarry District High School, Alexandria, ON

*High School Diploma (1997)

St. Lawrence College, Kingston, ON

*2-year Diploma

Harvord University, Online

*11-week Introduction to Python course completed

Toronto University, Online

*Coding Bootcamp 6-month course (start Feb 2022)

EXPERIENCE

ALEXANDRIA MOULDING

Administrator, July 2020 - Present

- Examining scorecards, Fill Rate and On Time weekly reporting, compiling issues from Territory and Area Managers for weekly overview with management
- Reviewing inventory and missed shipment opportunities with sites to determine corrective measures, tracking and summarizing units/dollars lost for review by Vice President
- Working with IT to create automated reports effectively reducing time spent pulling data and increasing speed to action time, identifying challenges in processes and coordinating between departments to initiate improvements
- Working with Planogram Lead and Systems Analyst to launch new ticket system facilitating communication from team in the field with administration and management
- Managing price adjustments across 1000+ SKU's to submit to Customer, inputting new costs in AX for all of Canada and USA, daily monitoring of potential pricing discrepancies to ensure changes are implemented and following up with Customer when necessary

CYBA STEVENS MANAGEMENT GROUP

Business Analyst/Account Manager, Dec 2012 - Sep 2019

- Managing key accounts in Grocery, Drug, Mass, Natural, Convenience and Gas Channels
- Sales and Commissions analysis across all vendors and retailers to identify and report on
 optimal revenue strategies. Data mining using AC Nielsen and other vendor, retailer, and
 distributor reports to understand sales by brand, size, and SKU and prepare revenue forecasts
- Providing management with reporting including profitability per category breakdown ranking, customer segment success, new listing opportunities and promotions vs ROI
- Liaison between Sales, Accounting and IT. Streamlining processes to improve communication and overall business flow between departments.
- Creating training/process documentation as necessary

GILMORE GLOBAL LOGISTIC SERVICES

Inventory Analyst/Account Manager, Oct 2011 - Aug 2012

- Regularly conducting customer meetings to discuss sales results, new promotions, any
 outstanding issues and potential growth opportunities. Working in concert with internal
 resources to ensure smooth implementation of new products/services and updating existing
 product lines for assigned accounts
- Creating reports to analyze products, sales and inventory levels and forecast new product order quantities, re-ordering points. Determining action for aged inventory. Present to Senior Managers for quarterly business reviews and survey/scorecard results and analysis

PLAYMOBIL CANADA INC

Analyst/Marketing Coordinator, Jun 2010 - Aug 2011

 Sales/inventory analysis responsibilities including forecasting production for 500+ SKU's, monitoring sales and inventory at store level, identifying opportunities and implementing plan of action based on findings, preparing presentations, discussing strategies with Sales
 Team, monitoring market trends, performing store visits to understand competition

JENO NEUMAN & FILS

Retail Analyst, Apr 2006 - Dec 2009

Analyzing customer buying trends as well as seasonal, regional and store specific trends.
 Completing sales and forecast reports with analysis on daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly and yearly basis to implement optimal strategies

SECOND CUP FRANCHISE

Co-Owner/Operator, Jun 2003 - Sep 2006

- Graduate of Second Cup School of Business, Second Cup headquarters
- Managing team of 12 to 18 employees. Interviewed, hired, terminated, trained, scheduled and budgeted for payroll
- Analyzing sales and inventory to determine re-ordering points, and best products for displays and holiday baskets. Phasing out of aged and slower moving items
- Completing daily cash spreadsheets, daily purchase logs, weekly cost reconciliation sheets, profit and loss statements and royalty reports
- Cost-effective marketing strategy, ranking #1 of 12 same category stores in St. Laurent Shopping Centre from second month of operating to date of selling